What if we could build a kind of seed from which, on a dead planet, life could blossom anew?
This's the A hole of Project Zero Don,
to create a super intelligent, fully automated, terra forming system and bring life back from lifelessness.
What was such a system require?
At its core?
It would need a true eh I fully capable of making the trillions of decisions necessary to reconstitute the biosphere.
An immortal guardian devoted to the re flourishing of life way.
Call it guy.
Mother Nature as an a
eclipse.
They're here.
Avoid contact lines.
Look.
Good guy.
It's up there.
Second floor.
Can you reach it?
So much for avoiding contacts.
No,
we're under a test.
I'm looking right at her.
Paris
Four.
Stay in cover.
They shadow
a gift from the shadow.
That's the last.
What?
Yeah.
No.
Finished?
Yeah.
Clear for a moment.
Anyway,
you have to find a guy
alert area inaccessible.
Elevator's non operational stairwells have collapsed.
Hello.
I'm Marga Ocean.
And this is a Festus.
As the name might tip you off.
This is going to be the subordinate function that guy will use to make loss and lots of robots.
her personal Ford.
Except it's not that simple.
Um, so, like you probably noticed that only about a third of you are robotics engineers, the rest experts, the machine commission, virtual heuristics, that stuff Well, that's because we aren't going to be the ones designing and building robots.
The last thing we want is to burden guy with a bunch of outmoded 21st century designs.
Waste of time.
Our purpose is to empower guy to build the robots and not just build.
Imagine from scratch any robot she needs for any conceivable purpose designed and fabricated at a snap of a finger purse.
Her finger.
So if Estes isn't really the Forge, it's more like the knowledge of craft and ingenuity of a master Smith to wield the hammer encoded a software virtual creativity made riel Guy's already learning in simulations.
She's doing some very creative things with fractal assembly and animal.
More apologies.
Her designs aren't about to win the PM prize anytime soon, but, hey, everyone has to start somewhere.
So yes, time to get started.
Let's do this.
I don't get it.
If if Estes was part of a system designed to save life, why wouldn't you sigh in to make a culture and turnout machines with no other purpose than to kill people.
Somehow it's gone broke.
I don't understand why,
but whatever the reason, that explains why machines have become more dangerous over the years,
from Mark Ocean to Elizabeth So back subject simulation results.
Wow, you weren't kidding about guys.
Pride.
Election for animal morphology.
ZX Sure.
Not totally unexpected, given the rough, natural terrain her box will have to navigate.
But I agree that there's something deeper going on here.
Her designs aren't just functional.
They feel almost like, Well, tributes is the word that comes to mind as though she's already mourning their loss, and not just for the disappearing fun of our time, but creatures from the fossil record two references to mega fauna and some of her designs.
So cool.
Well, whatever guy thinks up, have Festus will empower her to build it.
I just wish we could still be around in a century or two to see what she makes.
Margo
from Elisabet Sobek to Marco Shen.
Subject.
Full steam ahead.
Margaux.
If I doubted your brilliance in the slightest, I wouldn't have picked you as the Festus Alfa, you need to stop worrying about your agent communication style.
You are who you are.
Have confidence in yourself.
You know what you're doing.
Case in point.
The latest draught of your plan for the construction and stocking of bootstrap silos to store raw materials is excellent.
This, combined with your design for the A M foundry core in the foundry site selection plan, add up to a comprehensive plan.
It's time to start construction.
One detail.
Consult with Io Middle Kilo before you finalise the silo inventories.
First task will be to fabricate the robots that will construct the way foreign broadcast towers Minerva will use to transmit the deactivation codes, so any exotic materials needed for the towers should be accounted for in the inventory plan.
Elisabet
I've seen these shapes before in culture ins, but of course,
the briefing places of guys machines.
No,
I think this is this.
I was a bit so backs office, but it's sealed off.
There's got to be a way inside.
Keep looking
more eclipse.
Careful now.
Welcome to Apollo.
Collective memory off the human species and the rest ofthe knowledge for future generations.
I am Samina Budgie.
Until recently I was director of the International Collective Memory Institute in New Terror.
As a heritage professionals, I devoted my career to the preservation of human knowledge.
Creative endeavour on cultural achievement.
Apollo is therefore the ultimate embodiment of a lifelong passion, albeit under the very worst circumstances imaginable.
The challenges before us in minutes.
Specifically, we will have to design and implement for major initiative simultaneously.
First, the construction off data repositories incredible facilities around the world, ensuring redundancy.
Second, the collection and processing all the projected 180 million discreet data entries.
42 petabytes of data in Mandarin, English, Spanish and Arabic certain they're transferring and including off all that data onto D N A.
Encapsulated in synthetic Fossas, the only medium capacious and durable enough to safeguard it without degradation for the centuries to come.
And last but not least, the development off the holographic interface and game ified curricula by which future humans will commune with Apollo progressively unlocking heuristic learning modules, levelling up their knowledge and skills, they will need to take control of the terra forming system.
That is the future towards which all of our efforts would be directed.
No, just the preservation off the past, but the seed for the flourishing off a new tree off knowledge Welcome.
Let us begin
from Samina ever G two Elisabet Sobek subject encapsulated DNA, and the winner is encapsulated DNA.
Over the past 10 days, I performed an exhaustive review of data storage solutions magnetic, optical, quantum.
Even that attorney detect that fast was shielding a year or so ago.
But every other solution has one or more fatal shortcomings too heavy to transport.
Two massive to instal in the allotted space to power intensive over the centuries to prone to failure passed 300 to 400 years, et cetera.
Encapsulated DNA will easily hold the 40 plus Ceta bites were projecting.
For Apollo.
There are still many details to finalise, Of course.
To start with, we need to select the inert material in which we'll embed the molecules already testing 16 candidate materials as well as design and fabricate the power systems and sealed reliquaries that will keep the DNA at minus 18 degrees Celsius for 1000 plus years.
So long as I assure you that it didn't factor into my decision.
May I confess that I deem it entirely fitting, indeed, propitious, that we will be using the very building blocks of life to preserve human knowledge from mechanised extinction.
It's not just ironic, but heroic.
Life is the hero beating back the forces of oblivion.
In any case, much to dio until next time.
Peace be with you.
Samina
from Samina.
A biggie to Elisabet Sobek.
Subject.
Apollo Update.
Over the past two months, the full benefit of our procurement of a copy of the Homer Archive from Far Zenith has made itself known.
And as a result, all of Apollo's deliverables air on schedule.
Apollo has already surpassed 40 million discreet data entries and continues to grow.
The physical science modules are effectively complete with soft science modules close behind.
World history, cultural data and media archives are also on schedule.
Language preservation is wrapping up a bit ahead of schedule due to falling short of our goal to preserve 4500 languages.
I suppose the tragic early loss of popular in New Guinea doomed that go from the outset with attendant curricula development about to begin.
Speaking of the here is stick curriculum there performing well and testing with Children and adolescents demonstrating high levels of engagement with and trust in the Aristotle and US posse A persona.
Personally, I find them highly engaging, Especially when the debate I wish have my professors had been so entertaining.
Peace be with you, Samina.
Oh,
yeah.
Haven't you got anything better to do?
I've got a room.
That's the last of him Alone once more
in what should have been a cave of wonders.
Look around.
See if anything is left.
Okay,
you know?
Yeah.
Dr.
Sobek, please archive this testimonial in Apollo Cross reference to all mentions of my name at Operation Enduring Victory.
My name is General Aaron Harris.
From 2060 to 2066 I served as the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the highest ranked officer of the United States Armed Forces.
The tenure of my command included strategic planning, an oversight of Operation Enduring Victory, a false that perpetrated on the civilian populations in the United States on other nations during the last 14 months of life on this planet before the Pharaoh plague, I did my job and did it well.
I was bold and decisive.
Crafty and political manoeuvres.
It wasn't an accident that I rose to my position, became the commander of the largest mechanised force ever assembled.
But to what end?
My only lasting achievement
was the extinction of life on Earth.
On my one redeeming act, if any,
was to delay that extinction by days or weeks
by throwing Mohr death at it.
It is my hope, but there will be no need for men like me in the world to come.
If you are one of the people of that future world listening to this message,
please.
So that I am sorry.
And I wish you well sincerely.
Aaron Harris.
Welcome to Haiti's zero downs.
Extinction fail safe protocol.
The ultimate killer app.
Yeah, I know what you're thinking.
The purpose of a guy is to resurrect life.
So why give her a subordinate function?
Only purpose of which is to wipe out life all over again.
I mean, what the what?
Just some crazy Amy.
Well, no, isn't it?
Reconstituting a biosphere at Tall Tech?
Smartest guy.
Maybe odds are she won't get it right the first time.
I mean,
imagine your guy 200 years from now in this new bias for your growing, it's all gone wrong, alkaline, Just skyrocketing unit for his Fourth World.
Under the lash of super storms, I would've drowned Noah.
It's chaos spinning top the boom Stop, Robin, What you gonna do?
Release phase one organisms into that hot mess.
Hope their co two methane can balance out what you got started.
L know what you're gonna do.
Guy is step aside while Haiti's takes over and does what you're just too darn nurturing and life 11 to do, which is burned.
That misbegotten mental biosphere to the grounds of Guyana could start over okay, Not burned more like reverse terra forming operations and suffocated.
But you get the idea.
Haiti's takes the biosphere back to zero square, one blank late and then on Ly then doesn't hand the steering wheel back to guy and say, Try again a girl and better This time I will have to do this again, that Haiti's It's pretty bad ass when you think about it.
Extinction on demand, death on speed dial All for the greater good, of course, but still kind of medals.
So welcome to Haiti's welcome to the void.
Okay, so if that's the original purpose of Haiti's, why does it want me extinct?
And how does it end up in the wreckage of a pharaoh?
Tightened, Getting worshipped by the eclipse like some kind of God.
If a Festus, we're broke when that heat is, too.
That's what I'm thinking.
But why and what caused it?
Keep searching, and perhaps we'll find the answer.
From Samina effigy to Travis State CC Elizabeth Sobek Subject Archive abuse, Mr.
Date.
This male concerns Apollo Archives of Mission number 023876 year 666 Submission in just five days and oh, what a doozy.
Despite earlier warnings re inappropriate materials, you chose to submit 265 holographic re masters of acknowledged classics of extreme exploitation Cinema.
Allow me, then to thank you on two counts one for giving me the pleasure of rejecting your submission, thereby consigning your favourite Eastern European torture flicks and their ilk to the dust heap of oblivion.
It truly warms my heart to know that I have saved future humanity from the ordeal of experiencing not just one but all 16 instalments of making a militate.
Don't worry.
Pasolini material has already been preserved extreme perhaps, but hard to for clarifying a concept that has so long been ambiguous and ethically fraught.
For archivists such as myself, The definition of obscenity you have freed me from the subjective quagmire embodied in Judge Potter's famous utterance.
I know it when I see it.
Thanks to you, I can now apply a single objective criterion.
If Travis Tate submitted it, it's obscene.
Accordingly, I have directed Apollo staff to summarily reject all of your future submissions.
Sight unseen.
Perhaps you might invest the time you would have spent preparing further submissions on Oh, I don't know.
You're assigned work way.
Have a world to save, after all, for the rest of us do.
Anyway.
Dr.
Samina Effigy
from Travis State to Elizabeth Sobek.
Subject noise complaints.
Colour Me confounded Lizzie Bash Anyone who says the old TT codes to bash core is straight up lion and you know it all trapped.
Don't have no truck with commercialised razzle Daz.
Not a I'd rather guzzle a leader of sight.
Arun run off than listen to grace warm for 30 seconds.
Hand to God, I swear on my mama's grave and she was religious.
Now that ain't fast score blast in the Haiti's lab, shaking the walls rattling folks teeth.
It's death, metal girl, classical music.
Eighties and nineties mostly got me some Dutch death corps.
Some Japanese core grind some Swedish cannibal themed stuff too.
Stop by.
If you want to listen or, heck, just come within 50 metres of the lab.
Ain't no bash core you'll see or hear rather in the screech that rents the air and feel in the throbbing pulse of the floor and walls and ceiling swallowing you up like you was Jonah trapped in the gullet of Gothic death fish.
Hello, William.
As for those requests to turn it down, no can do, Lizzie.
This is how I code turned down my death metal might as well give up stimulants, chocolate months and industrial accident.
Vince Last I heard, we was supposed to be coding Haiti's down here.
Am I really supposed to code an extinction protocol without death metal to inspire me?
No, no, I don't think so.
Stay cool.
Trance
here Just popped three blues, but ironed.
It finally figured out a Goldilocks solution to guys rather extreme executive authority.
If that ain't worth 10 to 12 hours of dream time, what is before this Every user patient protocol I designed failed in simulation cause it was either too hard or too soft to hard, and it degraded the guy a core.
Sure, it pried her figurative fingers off the figurative driving wheels so Haiti's could take control.
But by breaking her fingers, sometimes your arms, too, so that couldn't fly.
Everything depends on God taking control back after Haiti's has done its business.
So had to find a solution that didn't leave Guy any worse for the wear too soft.
And I only pretended to relinquish control in simulation after simulation, Haiti's would take command of the terra forming system and reverse operations on ly to have guy alert in the background quietly re reversing processes and falsifying telemetry to hide its interference.
Sneaky, I swear, ain't nothing guy wouldn't do to keep life going even when it's just simulated plant life.
Turns out just right.
Solution is to isolate guy in a protective code shell, preserving its integrity than unseated from command positions.
So Haiti's Khun slip into the figurative captain's chair and work its magic.
Um, those blues air coming on strong now, so I'm not really describing it so clear, but pretty sure it'll work.
Yeah, those blues air plenty Strong's gives it's time to sleep in bed I'll back to with tomorrow.
Alligators.
Oh,
looks like the only way onwards.
Welcome to Lucia the Crown and King of Gods subordinate functions.
I thought he's value FIA that the human race will continue to exist.
I'm Patty Jacques Klein, the Alfa in charge of this programme.
Now let one thing be perfectly clear from the outset.
Sofia is not a genetic engineering project.
Our goal is to preserve the human genome, not alter it a snapshot of human genetic diversity literally frozen in time, the connected contestants of our species on modified under my watch, our activities and initiatives will comply with the 2034 clone provisions and the 2048 rally chords.
Now that may seem a quaint, even trivial, concerned to you in light of present circumstances.
But as one of the authors of the accords, it is far from trivial to me.
The practical challenges before us are staggering and scope on DH complexity but not insurmountable.
Global collision and provisional storage is our goods perfection of eggs, a genetic technologies design and perfection of Sir Vitter's to provide nurture and inculcation during early child development.
All of these programmes components must and will proceed intendant, to say nothing of the breakneck construction of crude oil facilities at sites around the world.
So
she was that pie.
Let us begin
from Patrick Bouchard, Klein to Elizabeth Sobek subject, said Chambers.
Thie Acta genic chambers arrived two days ago.
I've spent the last 36 hours examining them in pouring over technical documentation, their revelation astonishing.
I don't know what you had to give bars, anything trade to get these chambers, but it was worth it in a single leap there.
Embryologists had vaulted past 50 years of technological shortcomings.
The risks of ECMO resolved nutrition delivery resolved, hormonal stability resolved.
12 other risk areas resolved.
Before I examined these chambers, I considered the Odyssey to be a fool's errand.
But if the rest of that sets technologies at this level, well, a human colony around serious doesn't seem so impossible.
After all, mass fabrication of the chambers will present a number of challenges, but I'm confident they can be resolved.
I'm going to rest for a few hours, then get back to it.
Expected fabrication plan within 48 hours.
PPK
are these
What I what?
I think they were artificial wombs
machines to spawn a new generation of human beings.
From Patrick Bouchard, Klein to Elizabeth Sobek subject.
Cradle Servicer per Sony.
Development of the artificial persona for Cradle Sir Vitter's nurturer disciplinarian healer continues at a good pace.
We're targeting touring 0.4 for these constructs.
This should allow low, great empathy and limited improvisation without undermining adherence to codified behaviour sets.
The stimulus driven switching of persona, however, is proving to be a greater software challenge than anticipated, especially concerning our entrenched feedback loops between the disciplinarian and healer persona.
I have also attached the reports from an incident where a surveyor running the mother per Sony, intervened on a disciplinarian.
Sir Vitter's behaviour.
A parental argument, if you will.
A musing on first glance perhaps but deeply concerning.
I have attached a comprehensive plan for correcting these interactive protocol Shortcomings in just dated, corrupted
from Patrick Bouchard, Klein to Elizabeth Sobek subject.
Cradle sealed Lucia Owen was successfully sealed before the swarm advancing across Xinjiang Province could detect it.
Ping, back from crucial systems is good for our maiden voyage.
A success regards my disputes with the bait is oversight.
Go to selection?
Of course, I understand we have limited overhead to run simulations of gene flow in our future humans.
But we can all agree there is margin for refinement in future.
Cradle populations dunk.
In addition to personally overseeing completion of the two side inside mountain annually, I will formulate and propose a modified saiga selection plan within the week.
PPK
Cradle facilities.
I was a bit said a new generation of humans would be spawned inside such places.
She did
hall Mother Mountain.
It was one of them.
There's only one way to be sure
the hatch wouldn't open something.
Something about a corrupted Alfa registry.
I need to search Elizabeth's office.
Okay.
Pure logic will cut it.
Ted, to pull this off guy is going to need to have some skin in the game.
It has to care.
What if it runs amok?
We learned nothing from our mistakes.
Your mistakes, I think you mean All I'm saying is give it a kill switch.
She was just born Ted.
I'm not gonna put a gun to her head while she's still in the cradle.
You talk like it's such a child.
What if it becomes a monster?
It is a bit.
May I speak outside protocol?
Of course.
Get a go on.
I'm sorry to contradict you, but Mr Farrow's argument is sound.
At this point, the development of my psyche is not entirely predictable To ensure preservation of life.
Ah, hardwired override is, I believe, a necessary safeguard their satisfied Ted.
Jeez, let's just do what it says.
Looks like it used to hold something.
Some component that got removed.
That's what benefit from antelope in a morphology.
Ease, though.
Cap it forms show superior love.
Very incapability.
You're a quick study guy.
So back it doesn't have conducted this comparative analysis of more value.
More apologies.
I've gathered extensive data on the ordinary extinction event.
Oh, and your assessment
guy
logically speaking, the extinction was a natural consequence.
And yet, and yet I find the loss of mega for all species,
Captain
that they cast forever into oblivion causes me to experience.
Okay,
that is difficult to describe.
I'm a function.
No, no, you're not.
This is good.
It's very good.
Yeah.
He will undergo a brief period of unconsciousness during relocation to prime and final statement.
It was a bit.
We speak outside protocol.
When you're back up and running at the new site, we'll bring the subordinate functions online and see where we stand.
In is a bit I detect.
Dismiss.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I realised that circumstances compel us to launch earlier than we hoped.
That all some systems are operational.
The sand in our favour.
But what if
God, there's nothing left out there.
You can't even survive unless you're wearing an environmental suit there, Billy instead in fear and agony.
What if
What if it was all for nothing?
Isn't it?
Extinction was inevitable.
Thanks to you.
Life will have a future.
You really believe that?
I believe in you, Elizabeth.
And you all things
forget about travelling light
From Elizabeth Sobek to all Alphas.
Subject Odyssey has failed all some terrible news, I'm afraid far Zenith has informed me that the Odyssey mission has failed.
Last night, telemetry indicated a catastrophic antimatter containment failure is the drive's spun up to depart the solar system.
The ship, its crew, its cargo of zygotes and seeds.
It's Alfa build of Apollo.
All were lost.
Zero Don is now the only hope for the continuation of the human species and earthly life.
We must succeed Elizabeth
from Charles Bronson to Elizabeth.
So pick subject.
Artemus status.
It's coming along, Liz.
I'm positive about it.
If those words can still mean anything, had my sleeves rolled up negotiating with frozen suits for their samples.
So many species trapped in ghoulish hologram diagram is suspended in what ifs more than 14,000 that went extinct between 2000 and 2043.
We've started mapping out primary succession, selecting the pioneer organisms for a balanced and sustainable biosphere.
Microorganisms and insects, rabbits and hawks, foxes and wolves.
Thousands more that will have to wait their turn until our new generation can be entrusted with the duty of restoring them so they can return to a world that this time we'll understand the concept of conservation before it's too late.
There's already been too many too lates.
We lost a whole collection team during the swarm breakthrough in the booth samples.
We lost more well, irreplaceable.
But thanks to you, Liz, the circle of life will bend, not break.
The Earth was a lifeless rock before, and some day it will be again, but not now.
Not like this.
Not on our watch.
Bronson.
What the hell for registry?
Master file intact.
Yeah, No signs of corruption.
Then what are you waiting for?
Copy the file.
With this I can restore the registry at the hatch and said all Mother, open it.
Go inside and grasp secrets within where I was born.
Maybe
maybe you gave birth to me.
Who
are you really so naive?
There will be no waiting for you there.
A Loy.
Whatever birth do under the world was a what?
Not you bastard!
Oh, no.
I had a legitimate booth.
It's a you a lawyer who are the creation of a machine.
But what kind of machine and why?
Why were you created,
huh?
Eclipse.
You need to get out of this when you found is too valuable.
You're too valuable.
No,
Still alive.
Good.
I have a more suitable death in mind for you, child.
Haiti's takes a biosphere back to zero square, one blank slate and then on Ly then doesn't hand the steering wheel back to guy and say Try again.
Oh girl and better this time I will have to do this again that Haiti's It's pretty bad ass when you think about it